Today we have gathered here to do the puja of the Devi
The Devi has many forms but
is the embodiment of the shakti.
Adishakti gives shakti to all these embodiments.
And so there are many Goddesses we have at different times.
They came on this earth and did
all that was necessary for the ascent of people who were seekers.
Specially the one we know of Jagadamba, the Durga.
She was trying to protect all the seekers of truth
and to destroy all evil forces.
Because without the ascent of human beings,
they do not know the truth.
And that's why whatever they try to do
is a mental projection. And this mental projection,
if it is not substantiated by truth, by dharma, it declines.
In Sanskrit they call it 'glaani'.
When this glaani takes place
then incarnations are born to solve the problem.
In all incarnations of the Goddess, there have been,
very much incarnated the satanic forces.
They had incarnated and She had to fight them, with them
and destroy them.
But this destruction was not for the destruction sake that
the evil forces are to be destroyed
but evil forces always try to put down the seekers,
put down the saints, try to harm them, sometimes even destroy.
All these destructive forces do not come at the same time, normally
at different times. Is easy to handle
but the aim of the incarnation is to save,
to protect the people who are seekers
because they are the most important people
in the realm of spirituality. All others are nothing but dust,
good for nothing, useless. If they are not seeking the truth
in the eyes of God, they are just useless lives
that have come and will be finished.
They have no value and they have no dignity.
They have no understanding of anything.
So in the judgment of the divine love, we have two types of people:
one who are seekers of truth and the another who are not.
They may be good people. They will be nice people,
they'll be doing us lot of good works: social work, this work,
missionary work, every sort of work they might be doing.
But if they are not seeking the truth
then they do not come to that category
where God has to incarnate.
So try to understand the preciousness,
the importance of seekers.
And that's what you have been seeking.
Very few persons, if you take the percentage, are seeker.
Is very, very wee bit. But it's very important because, say,
a one little part of gold is much more valuable
than mounds of steel. In the same way, a seeker
is much more valuable in the growth of spirituality.
The whole universe was created,
whole atmosphere was built, all the evolution took place
for what? That human beings should know the truth.
But in the modern atmosphere,
it's a very big curse, I think the greatest evil
than all the Shumbha Nishumbhas and all that,
the worst of all is materialism
because materialism makes you gross.
In your seeking also when you are rising,
subtly that materialism catches you. I have been noticing this.
When people come to Sahaja Yoga, right,
they are going deep into themselves.
They are understanding what I am saying. All the inner knowledge
they want to know, what is called as Atmagyan.
Atmagyan means two things:
the knowledge about the spirit and knowledge about yourself.
All this they find out and they know what it is.
This state is the state for which people have been doing
all kinds of things: going to the Himalayas,
meditating in the cold without much clothes on them,
living in the caves with some fruits.
All kinds of tapasyas they would do because the seeking was so deep,
so urgent, and they could not get out of that force of seeking.
But in the modern times, materialism retards that hankering,
that dedication. It's maddening for people when they are seekers.
I have seen before coming to Sahaja Yoga, people spend lot of money,
go to various places, go to Himalayas, go to Nepal, go to Japan,
all over the places they are moving.
But after coming to Sahaja Yoga,
after they have become the spirits,
for the growth of your new awareness
the progress is retarded.
Also one should understand that after so much of running about,
you find something so precious so you settle down with that.
And you feel very satisfied about it. That part is all right.
But what later? Your growth should not stop.
And that stops because,
because of one of the main reasons is materialism.
Because of materialism,
your faith in yourself is also less.
Now as you have seen that the Gods prayed to the Goddess
and She came and killed all the negative forces.
Reason was: the earnest desire of the Gods
compelled Her to take incarnation.
Such sincere desire
that they could not get sometimes food, even water,
and they worked so hard for their ascent
which was disturbed by negative forces.
So their call was so from the heart,
so desperate and genuine and sincere
that the Goddess had to take birth on this earth
to save them, to protect them, to look after them.
But as it is, we see once you have reached a destination,
we feel now better settle down.
Now, what do you - we settle down with?
If after getting Realization you are complete,
you are in totality, you are absolutely one with reality,
there is nothing to be done.
You become a saint.
And a saint does not need any advertisement, does not need anything.
His message spreads. People see him and know
he is a great saint.
So many saints did not even leave their houses.
Very common saying in India,
"Your takiya you should not leave,"
the pillow on which you are resting, you should not leave.
That was a criteria of a guru. Those who have to seek
should come to the gurus and should climb up,
at least six seven miles up,
and then the guru doesn't meet any one.
He may slap you. He may hit you.
He may drop you from that high mountain.
He'll take your test by so many ways.
Ultimately he may select one person to give Realization.
So this hankering, this desperate effort
was all the time there.
Now so we come to Sahaja Yoga in this modern time.
Sometimes I feel that not only Sahaja Yoga is very easy
also it is extremely pampering. You know you have got Realization.
You all know that you are better than others,
that you have got rid of so many problems
and that now you have become master of your own.
Then the responsibility
that you have towards yourself and to your fellow men reduces
because you feel very satisfied with yourself.
The other day some Sahaja yogini rang Me up.
I mean, they ring Me up for everything.
She said that, "I went to the doctor and he put radiation
and they found I was pregnant so what should I do about the baby?"
For such a small thing they will ask.
"What should the name of our son?"
"What is this?" "What is that?"
I mean, I have to do much more work than any priest has to do.
Little, little things they are worried about. All right,
that part is all right that I have to tell you
what is to be done at such a point or what should we do.
If they miss the train, they will telephone to Me,
"Mother, we have missed the train. Now what to do?"
So I have to tell them, "All right, give them a bandhan."
That also I have to tell them.
Or supposing their father is sick. He has a heart trouble
then they will telephone to Me, "Mother, my father is sick.
He has a heart trouble. He is not a Sahaja yogi.
What can You do about it?" So Mother has to put attention
to his father who is not a Sahaja yogui.
Small, small things they write to Me.
Such small things that you can't imagine
how they do not understand what I am here for.
Still, I have never said that "It's a stupid thing to ask Me.
You should not waste My time," never.
But it is to be seen now
that if you do not value yourself as realized souls,
you can not value My time also
or what is Myself.
This incarnation can be wasted completely
because of this materialistic attitude.
In this modern times, I don't know
what's gone wrong with human beings
because the most important thing in your life
is to ascend and to grow.
Take a big vision of the whole thing.
Why this universe was created?
Why you were created as human beings?
What was the need to do all these things? For what is it done?
If you have a very big vision of the whole thing
then try to locate your position: "Where am I?!
And then, "How the Divine has selected me
and now I have become a Sahaja yogi?"
So now, "What is my responsibility?"
that one has to see.
But on the contrary, I have seen people
who are saying have a transfer. So they will telephone and ask,
"Mother, should we take our chair or not?"
That shows they have no value about themselves
and no value about Me, both ways.
Because they are asking such small things, such silly things
that is impossible to understand how
could Sahaja yogis ask such questions.
The perspective we can see: the Goddess.
She comes on this earth
in different forms at different times
to save the seekers of truth
and to work out the ascent of the seekers of truth.
Can you imagine?
A very big difference in the incarnation
of the Goddess before Kaliyuga.
While now, it's a very different thing
that you have come on this earth
to become the Sahaja yogis.
You have to have a body, a mind,
feeling everything which is just charged with spirituality,
charged with your spirituality.
Should be normally
because how many years in the past
you have been seeking God.
Then that came here. What a coincidence!
When, what is it? When you have such a great advantage
that you have come to Sahaja Yoga because of your seeking
and now you have found the satisfaction out of it.
What is the responsibility that you have?
That the incarnation Itself has come on this earth,
not only to protect you, to nourish you, and to kill the demons, no!
She has come on this earth
to tell you about everything that is subtler
inside and to tell you what should be
your relationship: should be outside as well as inside.
You were never connected with truth.
You were never connected with this all-pervading power.
You were never connected with God Almighty.
So one has to understand that,
"What a great thing has happened that out of me only,
this Kundalini has come out
and She has touched these higher centers." How?
This was not done before, no.
They were just protected. They were just looked after.
Nowhere it is written that "Goddess
has given Realization to people" nowhere.
She is responsible. She can give.
One of Her names is that. Not one but at least ten names are
that She gives you your nirvana, that She gives you your freedom,
that She introduces you to liberty.
All these things are written but what's happening now
is that people have not yet been able to grasp
the value of their life in the modern times.
See the way people ask questions.
See the way people, the inquiry is on,
the way people are worried,
"Now my child is big.
What should I do?" What should you do?
Child is big. Put him to school. Do what you like.
"Mother, will you please tell where to put the child."
Then you put the child."Have you seen the school, Mother?" "No, I haven't."
"Then you go and inspect the school."
Imagine Kali Mata doing that!
She would have given two nice tight slaps, I tell you.
Any body who would have said that, what do you make out of it?
But to that detailed extent a Motherhood has to work out.
You won't do that for your own child, I know.
But when it comes to children, what are they doing?
Still materialistic.
Today specially it's a very great day of Dussehra.
This is the day when, as you know, Ravana was burnt.
Effigies of Ravana were burnt all over the place.
When Shri Rama came this was done, His victory.
But in His victory,
it was not that He made Sahaja yogis
or He gave Realization, no.
His victory was that He killed Ravana.
That was done that time for today's preparation.
For today's happening, it was done long time back
that these days will come
when people will have proper value system of victory of Shri Rama.
But it doesn't happen.
It doesn't happen. Because this incarnation
of Mataji Nirmala Devi is very different, very illusive, Mahamaya.
So you are left to yourself,
do what you like. Whatever you like, you can do it.
So they will ask Me, "Mother, we have a problem."
I said, "What?" "We don't know which kind of chairs we should buy."
For every small thing they will refer to Mother
but for important things, never.
Sort of a funny use of the whole thing has started
which is so great, so important
is used for something absolutely nonsensical.
So see the difference between the incarnations.
One incarnation comes on this earth to save the people,
to bring them out of the mire of Maya.
But another incarnation which has come
is not only just to talk about it
but to give you your Realization
and then to look after your small, small things.
So when this lady telephoned and asked Me,
"What should I do? Please Mother, cure me."
It's very different attitude.
Between the bhaktas of those days
and the bhaktas of today, there's a very big difference.
I said, "You never asked Me
when you did all that, doesn't matter.
Now whatever you have done, it's better I see the child,
look after the child, put the child right but you come along."
But then I realized that this woman is so attached to her child.
And I telephoned to the leader
and he said, "It's terrible attachment.
It's a terrible attachment to the child."
So now from one nonsense to another nonsense.
This incarnation has such variety of jobs to be done.
I mean, even the 64 kalas, the 64 expertise
of Shri Ganesh is not sufficient to solve this.
Why is it so complicated? After giving Self- Realization,
it should be a straight forward march
towards your goal and towards your growth.
But why is it that such a complicated nonsense
is all the time bothering you?
What do you want? We should ask, "Now what do you want?"
"I want a child."
After Sahaja Yoga, you should not want anything.
"Why do you want to have a child? There are so many children.
You can look after them."
'I want' goes away, should go away from your mind that,
"I want this and I want that." This wanting is over now.
What you wanted: your Self-Realization.
After that, what has happened is that now:
what I want is more important and I want
that you should become really detached from materialism.
That doesn't mean
that you should become like "Hare Rama Hare Krishna" no, no, no, no.
They are not detached.
They are very much attached people. But detachment is a state where
nothing can bind you, nothing is important,
most important thing is your spiritual ascent.
Nothing can attract you more than this.
This is what exactly is wanted today,
that Sahaja yogis should understand.
Compared to what Sahaja yogis, compared to Sahaja yogis,
what people have gone through. When I read it everyday,
I feel terrible.
Here everything is convenience, convenient,
come along, enjoy nice food, nice company,
it's a festival going on. Everything is [inaudible].
And if something is missing, I will be the one
to tell the organizers, "What is this?
You should have done this. You should have done that."
Now, we come to a point where we have to understand:
What do we want?
What's the use of killing Shumbha Nishumbhas?
What's the use of killing this catholic church? What's the use?
Because you are static.
You are glued in one place, no progress.
So what's the use of doing all these things all the time
and destroying all that negativity.
What is the purpose?
It's too arbitrary, everybody says, "Mother,
you have given them permission. You have given them license,
so now they are doing the way they are."
The other day, one girl came to Me.
Her child was very sick. I asked her: "Do you meditate?"
She kept quiet.
I said I can make out that you don't meditate
because I know what it is.
That you don't even meditate?
So today's main thing is this is a Dussehra day
when the people go,
cross the boundaries of their villages
and bring gold for the parents.
That's the story, it is like that.
Now what you have to do is to
cross the limits of materialism, this nonsensical
dwarfy force that is working on you
and you have to transcend and bring, as I said, gold
that is untarnishable thing from the borders of Sahaja yoga.
How many of you really are in the field of work?
How many of you are telling about this to people?
What are you doing about it?
Why I am talking to you and not to Indians this way
because their attitude is different.
Their attitude is not materialistic. It's spiritual.
They want their spiritual ascent
for which they suffer a lot. They go out of the way to do things
just to get to that state where they could be easily surrendered.
This surrender state has to come.
For example, you have a problem.
Say problem, you have no holidays
and you want to come for Pujas, say. I'm just giving an example.
Now, if you want to come to Puja, you just come.
Not only you will get job but you might get promotion.
But you have no faith in your ascent.
You have no faith that you are the chosen one.
This is what is missing because of materialism.
Recently in America, we have a very great Sahaja yogi,
Dave Dunphy. I told him, "Dave,
you better take over as the leader of America
because this gentleman is not all right and you better take over."
Immediately he said, "All right Mother." Now, he lives in Honolulu.
Our programs and everything are done through L.A., Los Angeles,
and it looked quite strange that I should ask him
to come down and work there.
Now, where are we?
We are the people who have been blessed
with all the powers. You have been blessed.
But we don't want to practice.
We don't want to find out what powers we have,
worried about our own children,
worried about what sari we are going to wear,
or worried about who is the leader
and what should we do about the leadership.
All these things are not going to help us.
You are not here for that. Try to understand.
You are here for becoming the spirit
and then to spread the light of the spirit. Nothing matters.
Once you start doing that, you'll be amazed:
the faith works. It's not blind faith. It's not blind faith.
You don't have to tell Me even. It just works.
It's a matter a few days, you might get many results
of what you have been hankering after, material,
superficials, you might get. But the question remains.
Somebody, say, wants to dedicate his life, so called,
for Sahaja Yoga. Then what do you do?
What do you do if you dedicate?
First thing is your faith.
You must know: how is your faith into anything.
You really believe in it or you do not? If you do believe in it,
what have you done about it?
So at this stage, you have to introspect.
What are you doing?
What are we to do? How far do we have to go?
It's a very, very important time
and you are extremely important souls here sitting down
but, if you don't value your own systems and yourself,
why should God worry about you?
Why should God try to give you ideas?
Why should He try to take any interest even in you
persons of that [kind].
So now, I have to just tell you that on this day of this Puja,
it's such a combination that it is the Dussehra I am here,
and also is the now we can call it, the last day of the Devi Puja.
We have to see within ourselves, introspect:
"What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"
Except for looking after my children,
cooking for the husband, that's all?
Men can also think the same way: "What have we done?
What have we done for Sahaja Yoga?"
Just: I want to meet in the politicians.
I want to meet this person. I want to meet that person. For what?
They should come and meet you
but your faith in yourself is very weak.
I think that's the main reason for all this fall
is faith in yourself.
This faith is such a thing that you know it is.
You have seen My photographs.
You are convinced about it. There is nothing to be convinced
but this faith is not one with your heart.
It is not just with your being. It's outside.
All right, Mother will do that. Mother will solve this.
Mother will do this.
But, whole thing is now
to Me looks like, that I have to compulsorily tell you
to do some sort of a tapasya.
You ask somebody, "Do you meditate?" "No Mother," very plainly.
"No Mother, we don't." "So, what are you doing here?" "My,
My... there is some pain in my knees so I have come to you."
All right. "But I don't meditate. I am very honest.
I don't meditate.
I just have some pain in the knees. Please cure it.
I don't meditate."
How many of you really meditate every night?
Guido said that, "Mother, if You tell like this they will say,
'All right in the night we do but not in the morning'
because Mother has said, 'Do it in the night.'"
There is no earnestness.
There is no expected any kind of a enthusiasm about it.
All right, if not today, we will see tomorrow.
Mother says like that, "It's not necessary.
It's not important. It's all right."
So you satisfy yourself.
But who is the loser? Not Me. I don't need Sahaja Yoga, do I?
I am doing all the tapasya for your Sahaja Yoga.
What about you people doing some tapasya about it?
So now, what I am trying to say that you have got your Realization.
Now you have reached a great state of understanding,
also of the inner knowledge and also about your connection
with the spirit and with the God Almighty.
All this you know now. Many things you know.
Despite that, it's not yet what it should be from your heart.
From your earnest desire.
It doesn't help at all
any one to deceive oneself, never.
So I am not saying something for x, y, z.
I am saying for all of you. Don't try to cheat yourself.
You are here with such a great purpose.
This purpose is corrective
and is the freedom of our minds
from all these nonsensical destructive forces
and then to spread it all over, talk about it.
My own conviction is this
that something has to happen to Sahaja yogis
to realize how important it is
to work out something that is within us, which is potential,
which is just about to bubble up. It's a responsibility,
whether you are a Jew, a Christian or anything makes no difference.
It is all outside.
For what you have to do that you have come into a new realm
of awareness, into a new realm of a higher life
where you know all your inner self,
you know all about what is good and what is not.
Everything after knowing all this also if you do not grow
then whom will you blame?
So now we come to a point to understand
the importance of this Kaliyuga,
where your Mother is here to help you
and also to look after you
very tenderly, sweetly, to tell you everything.
Actually I can not get angry with any one for more than one minute.
So to explain to you sweetly what you should have done
and which you can do, which you have to do.
All these things I would have really
would have been telling you all the time.
I have been bringing you round very sweetly and explaining to you
and telling you that, "This is your own power
which is within you and which you have to look after and raise it",
and also you have got so many books
or ways of understanding that.
But this inner knowledge which you have
is something like this that I have a inner knowledge
about, say about, how to build these things
but I don't do it. It's as simple as that.
I just don't do it. I have the inner knowledge, all right.
I am a Ph.D. but I am mad. It's like that.
So many people mentally very well equipped in Sahaja Yoga, I know.
But as far as the following of Sahaja Yoga is concerned,
they are not there.
So I am warning you now.
It's like Christ has said, "some seeds which are sprouted
fell on the street, dried out and died."
Now the judgment is going on all the time.
When I am talking to you, it's all the judgment is going on.
So every night you have to meditate.
And you have to then think about what have you done tonight, today,
in the whole day what have you achieved.
But so calculating they are. Supposing I go there at five o'clock
then I have to be back at 7 otherwise I will miss the point,
I will not see this person, that person.
So, everything works like that:
with the time, with the importance of nonsensical things.
What has to work is your faith:
that I am going to do things
which are truthful, which are sensible, down to earth
and I'm going to keep myself absolutly extremely free and
and I'm going to look after not only my inner being
but the inner being of others.
Today's special puja is really of more Right side I would say,
Dussehra is a right side Puja
because you worship Shri Rama and his bow and everything.
But think of these incarnation. Fourteen years He went to jail.
For a particular reason, He went there.
I mean, if somebody has to go even for one year, it's a headache.
It's not a jail but it's, we can call, in the forest that He went,
it was like a jail to Him. He was a king's son.
He had no place to live, to sleep.
Everywhere He went, He had to build His own little hut.
So He went there. He had to do it.
Why, why did He do it?
Because He had faith in Himself. He is Shri Rama
and He has to jolly-well do these things.
He had faith in Himself. And He had faith in God Almighty
that whatever He is doing, He is doing as a will of God.
And that is what I have to do, finished.
I don't care whether I have to face Ravana
or I have to face this or that, I don't care.
I am a Sahaja yogi. I don't care.
My job is to spread Sahaja Yoga, all right.
My job is to cleanse myself up and know myself.
This is my work, my job, and this is what I have to do.
I am not bothered if I get admission in the school or not.
I am not bothered if somebody has to go by plane,
so he gets a ticket or not.
You just won't believe
that you show your faith in yourself,
you'll get the admission, you'll get the ticket,
whatever you want it's there. It's all there.
You don't have to strive for it.
You don't have to bother for it. It's just there.
It is. I mean, all My life it has been happening.
Of course My faith is like solid, like Gibraltar, no question.
Because I know what I am and I know what I am supposed to do.
So My, for Me I have no problem.
All the faith and I know everyone
and I can say that I can make out a flying bird.
May not show that. Sometimes I may say that, all right
this is good, this is that, but I know for definite
what I am and what I have to do.
In the same way, you have to know about yourself
because it is a different category of people you are.
You are not the ones who need protection from God,
who need protection from the Mother, no.
You have to give protections to others.
It is you have to give light to others.
You have to show them the path.
So you are here for that purpose not for getting a house
or a, what you call, income tax concession.
You are not that for. All that nonsense you forget.
Jolly-well, they'll have to give you concession.
I, I live like that, absolutely. I am not bothered
when I am traveling, whether there's a ticket or not
whether there is, what you call, a seat or not. I am not bothered.
I am not bothered at all. All right I am traveling.
I don't even think I am traveling.
I just think that I am there. That's all.
So many things I say
which looks so bombastic and looks so ego oriented,
like I said, "This catholic church is about to finish."
I said that. If it was someone else they'll say, "Perhaps, maybe."
Now, so one has to change one's own language, the style.
And our understanding should be that we are a rough people.
We are rough as far as ourselves are concerned.
With others we are kind, tender, and sweet.
But as far as we are concerned, we are not.
Once it happened, we had a transfer
and we went into a house, very big house though,
but there was nothing to sleep upon. There was one bed,
very small. My husband was sleeping. He just can't do like that.
I said, "All right, take a challenge." I slept on the ground.
Next day, I had pain in the body. I told My body,
"Behave yourself. You must learn how to sleep on stones also."
And for one month I was sleeping on the ground, still.
So you have to be harsh with your body.
You have to be harsh with your mind which gives you ideas
of materialism or of retarding your progress in spirituality.
Now, escapes, escapes they find out.
Ultimately, you come to the last point
where you do not think about, say, material life
and you don't think of mental life
or so called these spiritual lives or anything but you think that
it's all right, you are free from it and now you have become
a very, very free person and you can do what you like.
Supposing you reach a state like that then you just say, "Oh,
I have reached that state, finished." How are we to believe?
What's the proof that you have reached that state?
You must show. Doesn't show but they say, "Ah, we are."
There is a myth also in Sahaja Yoga:
that senior, he is a very senior Sahaja yogi.
I mean, I don't understand.
What is this? How can there be seniority in Sahaja yoga?
Cannot be seniority. No question.
Somebody is say, enters into the sea.
Some are there for ages standing near the edge
of the sea holding on to the earth
because they are afraid to swim
and some people who have come only yesterday
might be jumping and going ahead and doing, enjoying the sea.
So how is it he is the senior?
We do not have this seniority business in Sahaja yoga.
There's no seniority.
And there's also another myth. Maybe this is an excuse. I don't know
what to say but it is a very common thing to say
that he is a senior Sahaja yogi or he is a,
after all he is a senior Sahaja yogi.
Can't understand.
Like saying a donkey,
"This donkey is senior. Another donkey is not."
Then another thing that you suffer from very much
much, very common is this that "Mother said so."
Anybody will say, "Oh, Mother said to me,
She called me and She said it."
"What did She say?" "Oh you are a very great Sahaja yogi.
You are this. You are that. You are that."
Now there are two possibilities.
One, I might have said it just to befool him.
I am Mahamaya.
Or maybe I must have said all this just to see that pamper his ego
so that he gets to Sahaja Yoga
and does something substantial than to eat my head.
So, "Mother said so." Such a great Sahaja yogi,
I am such and such, very bombastic words,
very bombastic language he would use.
And then people, "Ah, what a Sahaja yogi!"
So the judgment of a Sahaja yogi doesn't come from what he claims
but what he achieves.
I have seen some Sahaja yogis are extremely arrogant also.
Extremely arrogant,
think no end of themselves. All that is there.
So many Sahaja yogis I have seen of that kind,
that they are very, very arrogant
and that they try to make a big show
out of what great people they are.
Humpty Dumpties, as they call them.
All right, but what a Sahaja yogi who is not like that,
what is his style is?
He'll just watch. He will witness the whole thing
just enjoy and laugh at what is happening.
What is this man talking like this?
What's the sense of his talking like this?
A person who is a Sahaja yogi is a gem.
Is a gem and gem for which you take him to anywhere, to any place,
people will say he is a gem.
My own style is this that when I see a person
or a Sahaja yogi anywhere, first thing I go inside Myself,
first thing. I don't know if you can do that. I can.
And then I see that person in a very different perspective
and understand. Because all these powers are with you also.
It's not My powers only, you all have these powers
but the only difference between you and Me
is that I have all faith in Myself
and you have no faith in yourself.
So we are at a crossing roads where we have to understand
who will go higher and who will go lower.
You have to find out who is the one
who is going to achieve something
and where am I compared to that person.
It's said, "You have to suffer. You have to do this.
You have to do that." Nothing of the kind, by God's grace.
Nothing of that kind.
So now what is it? What will happen to a Sahaja yogi?
How will you know who is a Sahaja yogi?
How will you know who is just putting a lip service?
Only way is that you evolve.
You become like a mirror
and you see for yourself what sort of a person he is
and also you see yourself, what you are.
Today's lecture is more, sort of,
is actually absolutely inspired lecture.
And it is the one that should tell you
that all that we have done today
is this to understand our own values about our own life.
We should understand: "Why are we on this earth?
What is our purpose and what you have to achieve?"
See, this I give you My all blessings from My heart.
And I want you to accept My blessings,
to be the great lights of God's desire.
Try to understand what important time you are born
and that you have become such good, beautiful people of God.
May God bless you!